<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">

<channel>
<ttl>60</ttl>
<title>EconTalk Archives, 2007</title>
<link>http://www.EconTalk.org</link>
<language>en-us</language>
<copyright>&#xA9; 2006-2013 Library of Economics and Liberty &amp; Liberty Fund, Inc.</copyright>

<description>EconTalk is an award-winning weekly talk show about economics in daily life. Featured guests include renowned economics professors, Nobel Prize winners, and exciting speakers on all kinds of topical matters related to economic thought.  Topics include health care, free trade, economic growth, education, finance, politics, sports, book reviews, parenting, and the curiosities of everyday decision-making. Russ Roberts, of the Library of Economics and Liberty and George Mason U., draws you in with lively guests and creative repartee.  Look for related readings and the complete archive of previous shows at EconTalk.org, where you can also comment on the podcasts and ask questions.</description> 

<itunes:subtitle>Economics Brought to Life, Library of Economics and Liberty</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts, Library of Economics and Liberty</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary>EconTalk is an award-winning weekly talk show about economics in daily life. Featured guests include renowned economics professors, Nobel Prize winners, and exciting speakers on all kinds of topical matters related to economic thought.  Topics include health care, free trade, economic growth, education, finance, politics, sports, book reviews, parenting, and the curiosities of everyday decision-making. Russ Roberts, of the Library of Economics and Liberty (econlib.org) and George Mason U., draws you in with lively guests and creative repartee.  Look for related readings and the complete archive of previous shows at EconTalk.org, where you can also comment on the podcasts and ask questions.</itunes:summary>

<itunes:new-feed-url>http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/EconTalk2007.xml</itunes:new-feed-url>


<itunes:owner>
<itunes:name>Library of Economics and Liberty</itunes:name>
<itunes:email>webmaster@econlib.org</itunes:email>
</itunes:owner>
<itunes:image href="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/EconTalkCDcover1400y2007.jpg" />
<itunes:category text="Education">
<itunes:category text="Higher Education"/>
</itunes:category>
<itunes:category text="Science &amp; Medicine">
<itunes:category text="Social Sciences"/>
</itunes:category>
<itunes:category text="Business"/>
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>

<item>
<title>Duggan on Strategic Intuition</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2007 06:15:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>William Duggan, professor of management at Columbia Business School at Columbia University, talks about his latest book, Strategic Intuition. Duggan critiques traditional methods of strategy and planning and suggests that the opportunism and adaptability are more productive detailed plans. He also discusses the nature of intuition and creativity along with insights into how the brain works to better understand problem-solving.</description>
<itunes:summary>William Duggan, professor of management at Columbia Business School at Columbia University, talks about his latest book, Strategic Intuition. Duggan critiques traditional methods of strategy and planning and suggests that the opportunism and adaptability are more productive detailed plans. He also discusses the nature of intuition and creativity along with insights into how the brain works to better understand problem-solving.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>William Duggan talks about his latest book, Strategic Intuition. Duggan critiques traditional methods of strategy and planning and suggests that the opportunism and adaptability are more productive detailed plans. He also discusses the nature of intuition and creativity along with insights into how the brain works to better understand problem-solving.</itunes:subtitle>

<itunes:keywords>economics, William Duggan,strategy,brain, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Dugganstrategy.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Dugganstrategy.mp3" length="26638836" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>55:30</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Karol Boudreaux on Property Rights and Incentives in Africa</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2007 06:30:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Karol Boudreaux, Senior Research Fellow at George Mason University's Mercatus Center, talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about her field work and research in Rwanda and South Africa. In Rwanda, she studied how a change in incentives and property rights for coffee farmers has allowed the coffee bean growers to improve quality and prosper. In South Africa's Langa Township, she looked at how renters were allowed to become homeowners and how the ability to own changed their lives.</description>

<itunes:summary>Karol Boudreaux, Senior Research Fellow at George Mason University's Mercatus Center, talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about her field work and research in Rwanda and South Africa. In Rwanda, she studied how a change in incentives and property rights for coffee farmers has allowed the coffee bean growers to improve quality and prosper. In South Africa's Langa Township, she looked at how renters were allowed to become homeowners and how the ability to own changed their lives.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Karol Boudreaux talks with host Russ Roberts about her field work and research in Rwanda and South Africa. In Rwanda, she studied how a change in incentives and property rights for coffee farmers has allowed the coffee bean growers to improve quality and prosper. In South Africa's Langa Township, she looked at how renters were allowed to become homeowners and how the ability to own changed their lives.</itunes:subtitle>

<itunes:keywords>economics, Karol Boudreaux,africa,coffee,rwanda,langa township,econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/BoudreauxKafrica.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/BoudreauxKafrica.mp3" length="29017024" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>1:00:27</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Boettke on Austrian Economics</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2007 06:00:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Pete Boettke, of George Mason University, talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about the origins and tenets of Austrian economics. This is a wonderful introduction to how the so-called Austrian economists look at the world and how they continue to influence economics today.</description>
<itunes:summary>Pete Boettke, of George Mason University, talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about the origins and tenets of Austrian economics. This is a wonderful introduction to how the so-called Austrian economists look at the world and how they continue to influence economics today.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Pete Boettke talks with host Russ Roberts about the origins and tenets of Austrian economics. This is a wonderful introduction to how the so-called Austrian economists look at the world and how they continue to influence economics today.</itunes:subtitle>

<itunes:keywords>economics, Pete Boettke,austrian school, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Boettkeaustrian.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Boettkeaustrian.mp3" length="37390836" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>1:17:54</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Munger on Fair Trade and Free Trade</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2007 06:30:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Mike Munger, frequent guest and longtime Econlib contributor, speaks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about fair trade coffee and free trade agreements. Does the premium for fair trade coffee end up in the hands of the grower? What economic forces might stop that from happening? They discuss the business strategy of using higher wages as a marketing strategy to attract concerned consumers. They turn to the issue of free trade agreements. If the ideal situation is open borders to foreign products, is it still worthwhile to negotiate bilateral and multilateral agreements that requires delays, exemptions and a bureaucracy to enforce? What is the cost of including environmental and various labor market regulations in these agreements?</description>
<itunes:summary>Mike Munger, frequent guest and longtime Econlib contributor, speaks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about fair trade coffee and free trade agreements. Does the premium for fair trade coffee end up in the hands of the grower? What economic forces might stop that from happening? They discuss the business strategy of using higher wages as a marketing strategy to attract concerned consumers. They turn to the issue of free trade agreements. If the ideal situation is open borders to foreign products, is it still worthwhile to negotiate bilateral and multilateral agreements that requires delays, exemptions and a bureaucracy to enforce? What is the cost of including environmental and various labor market regulations in these agreements?</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Mike Munger, frequent guest and longtime Econlib contributor, speaks with host Russ Roberts about fair trade coffee and free trade agreements. Does the premium for fair trade coffee end up in the hands of the grower? What economic forces might stop that from happening? They discuss the business strategy of using higher wages as a marketing strategy to attract concerned consumers. Is it worthwhile to negotiate bilateral and multilateral agreements? What is the cost of including environmental and various labor market regulations in these agreements?</itunes:subtitle>

<itunes:keywords>economics, Mike Munger,free trade,coffee, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Mungertrade.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Mungertrade.mp3" length="28303776" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>58:58</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Botkin on Nature, the Environment and Global Warming</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2007 06:00:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Daniel Botkin, ecologist and author, talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about how we think about our role as humans in the natural world, the dynamic nature of environmental reality and the implications for how we react to global warming.</description>
<itunes:summary>Daniel Botkin, ecologist and author, talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about how we think about our role as humans in the natural world, the dynamic nature of environmental reality and the implications for how we react to global warming.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Daniel Botkin, ecologist and author, talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about how we think about our role as humans in the natural world, the dynamic nature of environmental reality and the implications for how we react to global warming.</itunes:subtitle>

<itunes:keywords>economics, Daniel Botkin,environment,global warming, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Botkinnature.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Botkinnature.mp3" length="31820694" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>1:06:18</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Sunstein on Worst-case Scenarios</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2007 06:30:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Cass Sunstein of the University of Chicago talks about the ideas in his latest book, Worst-Case Scenarios. How should individuals and societies cope with low-probability events with potentially catastrophic consequences? In this conversation with EconTalk host Russ Roberts, Sunstein discusses the uselessness of the precautionary principle as a guide to behavior and the psychological challenges we all face in coping with uncertain, risky events. He also speculates why we have chosen politically to treat terrorism and global warming so differently.</description>
<itunes:summary>Cass Sunstein of the University of Chicago talks about the ideas in his latest book, Worst-Case Scenarios. How should individuals and societies cope with low-probability events with potentially catastrophic consequences? In this conversation with EconTalk host Russ Roberts, Sunstein discusses the uselessness of the precautionary principle as a guide to behavior and the psychological challenges we all face in coping with uncertain, risky events. He also speculates why we have chosen politically to treat terrorism and global warming so differently.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Cass Sunstein talks about the ideas in his latest book, Worst-Case Scenarios. How should individuals and societies cope with low-probability events with potentially catastrophic consequences? In this conversation with host Russ Roberts, Sunstein discusses the uselessness of the precautionary principle as a guide to behavior and the psychological challenges we all face in coping with uncertain, risky events. He also speculates why we have chosen politically to treat terrorism and global warming so differently.</itunes:subtitle>

<itunes:keywords>economics, Cass Sunstein,risk, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Sunsteinworstcase.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Sunsteinworstcase.mp3" length="30930650" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>1:04:36</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Henry Aaron on Health Care Costs</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2007 06:40:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>In this bonus middle-of-the-week podcast, Henry Aaron of the Brookings Institution talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about health care costs. Researchers in a New England Journal of Medicine article have estimated that the US could save $209 billion if the US went to a single-payer system like Canada. Is this number reliable? Aaron takes a deeper look at the estimate and discusses the relevance of such estimates for health care policy. This is a special mid-week podcast. It's a follow-up to an earlier podcast with Arnold Kling that raised the issue of administrative costs and potential savings from going to a single-payer system. It also ties in with recent discussions here at EconTalk about the challenges of accurate measurement in the social sciences. We hope you enjoy it. If not, come back Monday when our regular schedule resumes.</description>
<itunes:summary>In this bonus middle-of-the-week podcast, Henry Aaron of the Brookings Institution talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about health care costs. Researchers in a New England Journal of Medicine article have estimated that the US could save $209 billion if the US went to a single-payer system like Canada. Is this number reliable? Aaron takes a deeper look at the estimate and discusses the relevance of such estimates for health care policy. This is a special mid-week podcast. It's a follow-up to an earlier podcast with Arnold Kling that raised the issue of administrative costs and potential savings from going to a single-payer system. It also ties in with recent discussions here at EconTalk about the challenges of accurate measurement in the social sciences. We hope you enjoy it. If not, come back Monday when our regular schedule resumes.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>In this bonus mid-week podcast, Henry Aaron  talks with host Russ Roberts about health care costs. Researchers in a New England Journal of Medicine article have estimated that the US could save $209 billion if the US went to a single-payer system like Canada. Is this number reliable? Aaron takes a deeper look at the estimate and discusses the relevance of such estimates for health care policy. This is a follow-up to an earlier podcast with Arnold Kling.</itunes:subtitle>

<itunes:keywords>economics, Henry Aaron,health care, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Aaronhealth.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Aaronhealth.mp3" length="19000214" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>39:35</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Waldfogel on Markets, Choice, and the Tyranny of the Market</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2007 06:30:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Joel Waldfogel of the Wharton School of Business talks about the idea in his new book, The Tyranny of Markets: Why You Can't Always Get What You Want. He argues that when fixed costs are large, markets don't necessarily give people what they want and that, analogous to the political process, you can be hurt as the number of people with preferences that differ from yours gets larger. Host Russ Roberts challenges Waldfogel's claim that these phenomena are widespread and argues that in many cases, markets ultimately solve these problems. They discuss the amount of variety in newspapers, radio, and airline travel, along with how economics generally looks at fixed costs and consumer sovereignty.</description>
<itunes:summary>Joel Waldfogel of the Wharton School of Business talks about the idea in his new book, The Tyranny of Markets: Why You Can't Always Get What You Want. He argues that when fixed costs are large, markets don't necessarily give people what they want and that, analogous to the political process, you can be hurt as the number of people with preferences that differ from yours gets larger. Host Russ Roberts challenges Waldfogel's claim that these phenomena are widespread and argues that in many cases, markets ultimately solve these problems. They discuss the amount of variety in newspapers, radio, and airline travel, along with how economics generally looks at fixed costs and consumer sovereignty.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Joel Waldfogel talks about the idea in his new book, The Tyranny of Markets. He argues that when fixed costs are large, markets don't necessarily give people what they want and that, analogous to the political process, you can be hurt as the number of people with preferences that differ from yours gets larger. Host Russ Roberts challenges Waldfogel's claim that these phenomena are widespread and argues that in many cases, markets ultimately solve these problems.</itunes:subtitle>

<itunes:keywords>economics, Joel Waldfogel,markets,fixed costs, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Waldfogelmarkets.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Waldfogelmarkets.mp3" length="24809847 " type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>51:41</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Arnold Kling on the Economics of Health Care and the Crisis of Abundance</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2007 06:30:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Arnold Kling of EconLog talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about the economics of health care and his book, A Crisis of Abundance: Rethinking How We Pay for Health Care. Kling discusses whether we get what we pay for when we spend money on health care, why health care isn't like cars, and why health care insurance isn't really insurance. The conversation closes with a discussion of innovation in America's health care system and why America is so unlike everywhere else.</description>
<itunes:summary>Arnold Kling of EconLog talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about the economics of health care and his book, A Crisis of Abundance: Rethinking How We Pay for Health Care. Kling discusses whether we get what we pay for when we spend money on health care, why health care isn't like cars, and why health care insurance isn't really insurance. The conversation closes with a discussion of innovation in America's health care system and why America is so unlike everywhere else.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Arnold Kling talks with host Russ Roberts about the economics of health care and his book, A Crisis of Abundance: Rethinking How We Pay for Health Care. Kling discusses whether we get what we pay for when we spend money on health care, why health care isn't like cars, and why health care insurance isn't really insurance. The conversation closes with a discussion of innovation in America's health care system and why America is so unlike everywhere else.</itunes:subtitle>

<itunes:keywords>economics, Arnold Kling,abundance,health care, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/klinghealthcare.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Klinghealthcare.mp3" length="28265115" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>58:53</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Yandle on the Tragedy of the Commons and the Implications for Environmental Regulation</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2007 06:30:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Bruce Yandle of Clemson University and George Mason University's Mercatus Center looks at the tragedy of the commons and the various ways that people have avoided the overuse of resources that are held in common. Examples discussed include fisheries, roads, rivers and the air. Yandle talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about the historical use of norms, cooperative ventures such as incorporating a river, the common law, and top-down command-and-control regulation to reduce air and water pollution.</description>
<itunes:summary>Bruce Yandle of Clemson University and George Mason University's Mercatus Center looks at the tragedy of the commons and the various ways that people have avoided the overuse of resources that are held in common. Examples discussed include fisheries, roads, rivers and the air. Yandle talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about the historical use of norms, cooperative ventures such as incorporating a river, the common law, and top-down command-and-control regulation to reduce air and water pollution.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Bruce Yandle looks at the tragedy of the commons and the various ways that people have avoided the overuse of resources that are held in common. Examples discussed include fisheries, roads, rivers and the air. Yandle talks with host Russ Roberts about the historical use of norms, cooperative ventures such as incorporating a river, the common law, and top-down regulation to reduce pollution.</itunes:subtitle>

<itunes:keywords>economics, Bruce Yandle,pollution,resources,common law, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Yandlecommons.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Yandlecommons.mp3" length="40577357" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>1:24:32</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Ayres on Super Crunchers and the Power of Data</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2007 06:00:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Ian Ayres of Yale University Law School talks about the ideas in his new book, Super Crunchers: Why Thinking-by-Numbers Is the New Way to Be Smart. Ayres argues for the power of data and analysis over more traditional decision-making methods using judgment and intuition. He talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about predicting the quality of wine based on climate and rainfall, the increasing use of randomized data in the world of business, the use of evidence and information in medicine rather than the judgment of your doctor, and whether concealed handguns or car protection devices such as LoJack reduce the crime rate. The podcast closes with a postscript by Roberts challenging the use of sophisticated statistical techniques to analyze complex systems.</description>
<itunes:summary>Ian Ayres of Yale University Law School talks about the ideas in his new book, Super Crunchers: Why Thinking-by-Numbers Is the New Way to Be Smart. Ayres argues for the power of data and analysis over more traditional decision-making methods using judgment and intuition. He talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about predicting the quality of wine based on climate and rainfall, the increasing use of randomized data in the world of business, the use of evidence and information in medicine rather than the judgment of your doctor, and whether concealed handguns or car protection devices such as LoJack reduce the crime rate. The podcast closes with a postscript by Roberts challenging the use of sophisticated statistical techniques to analyze complex systems.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Ian Ayres talks about the ideas in his new book, Super Crunchers: Why Thinking-by-Numbers Is the New Way to Be Smart. Ayres argues for the power of data and analysis over more traditional decision-making methods using judgment and intuition. He talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about predicting the quality of wine based on climate and rainfall, the increasing use of randomized data in the world of business, and more.</itunes:subtitle>

<itunes:keywords>economics, Ian Ayres,supercrunchers,lojack,statistics, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Ayresdata.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Ayresdata.mp3" length="30112704" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>1:02:44</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Robert Frank on Economics Education and the Economic Naturalist</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2007 06:00:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Author Robert Frank of Cornell University talks about economic education and his recent book, The Economic Naturalist. Frank argues that the traditional way of teaching economics via graphs and equations often fails to make any impression on students. In this conversation with host Russ Roberts, Frank outlines an alternative approach from his new book, where students find interesting questions and enigmas from everyday life. They then try to explain them using the economic way of thinking. Frank and Roberts discuss a number of the enigmas and speculate on the future of economics and education. The topics discussed include tuxedos vs. wedding dresses, the level of civility (or lack thereof) in New York City, the difference between vending machines for soda and newspapers, the tragedy of the commons, and the economics of love.</description>
<itunes:summary>Author Robert Frank of Cornell University talks about economic education and his recent book, The Economic Naturalist. Frank argues that the traditional way of teaching economics via graphs and equations often fails to make any impression on students. In this conversation with host Russ Roberts, Frank outlines an alternative approach from his new book, where students find interesting questions and enigmas from everyday life. They then try to explain them using the economic way of thinking. Frank and Roberts discuss a number of the enigmas and speculate on the future of economics and education. The topics discussed include tuxedos vs. wedding dresses, the level of civility (or lack thereof) in New York City, the difference between vending machines for soda and newspapers, the tragedy of the commons, and the economics of love.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Author Robert Frank talks about economic education and his recent book, The Economic Naturalist. Frank argues that the traditional way of teaching economics via graphs and equations often fails to make any impression on students. In this conversation with host Russ Roberts, Frank outlines an alternative approach from his new book. Topics include tuxedos vs. wedding dresses, civility in NYC, vending machines, the tragedy of the commons, and the economics of love.</itunes:subtitle>

<itunes:keywords>economics, Robert Frank,naturalist,education,supply,demand, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Franknaturalist.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Franknaturalist.mp3" length="33142072" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>1:09:03</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>McCraw on Schumpeter, Innovation, and Creative Destruction</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2007 07:00:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Thomas McCraw of Harvard University talks about the ideas of Joseph Schumpeter from his book, Prophet of Innovation: Joseph Schumpeter and Creative Destruction. McCraw and EconTalk host Russ Roberts discuss innovation, business strategy, the role of mathematics in economics, and Schumpeter's vision of competition embodied in his most important idea--creative destruction.</description>
<itunes:summary>Thomas McCraw of Harvard University talks about the ideas of Joseph Schumpeter from his book, Prophet of Innovation: Joseph Schumpeter and Creative Destruction. McCraw and EconTalk host Russ Roberts discuss innovation, business strategy, the role of mathematics in economics, and Schumpeter's vision of competition embodied in his most important idea--creative destruction.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Thomas McCraw talks about the ideas of Joseph Schumpeter from his book, Prophet of Innovation: Joseph Schumpeter and Creative Destruction. McCraw and host Russ Roberts discuss innovation, business strategy, the role of mathematics in economics, and Schumpeter's vision of competition embodied in his most important idea--creative destruction.</itunes:subtitle>

<itunes:keywords>economics, Thomas McCraw,innovation,creative destruction,Schumpeter, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Mccrawinnovation.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Mccrawinnovation.mp3" length="32022986" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>1:06:43</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Boudreaux on Market Failure, Government Failure and the Economics of Antitrust Regulation</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 06:30:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Don Boudreaux of George Mason University talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about when market failure can be improved by government intervention. After discussing the evolution of economic thinking about externalities and public goods, the conversation turns to the case for government's role in promoting competition via antitrust regulation. Boudreaux argues that the origins of antitrust had nothing to do with protecting consumers from greedy monopolists. The source of political demand for antitrust regulation came from competitors looking for relief from more successful rivals.</description>
<itunes:summary>Don Boudreaux of George Mason University talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about when market failure can be improved by government intervention. After discussing the evolution of economic thinking about externalities and public goods, the conversation turns to the case for government's role in promoting competition via antitrust regulation. Boudreaux argues that the origins of antitrust had nothing to do with protecting consumers from greedy monopolists. The source of political demand for antitrust regulation came from competitors looking for relief from more successful rivals.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Don Boudreaux talks with host Russ Roberts about when market failure can be improved by government intervention. They discuss the evolution of economic thinking about externalities and public goods and the government's role in promoting competition via antitrust regulation. Boudreaux argues that the origins of antitrust had nothing to do with protecting consumers from greedy monopolists but rather came from competitors looking for relief from more successful rivals.</itunes:subtitle>

<itunes:keywords>economics, Don Boudreaux,antitrust,monopoly, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Boudreauxantitrust.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Boudreauxantitrust.mp3" length="31943783" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>1:06:33</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Grab Bag: Munger and Roberts on Recycling, Peak Oil and Steroids</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2007 06:30:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Mike Munger, of Duke University, and EconTalk host Russ Roberts clean up some loose ends from their previous conversation on recycling, move on to talk about the idea of buying local to reduce one's carbon footprint and then talk about the idea of peak oil. They close the conversation with the Rick Ankiel story and the implications for the Barry Bonds saga.</description>
<itunes:summary>Mike Munger, of Duke University, and EconTalk host Russ Roberts clean up some loose ends from their previous conversation on recycling, move on to talk about the idea of buying local to reduce one's carbon footprint and then talk about the idea of peak oil. They close the conversation with the Rick Ankiel story and the implications for the Barry Bonds saga.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Mike Munger and host Russ Roberts clean up some loose ends from their previous conversation on recycling, talk about the idea of buying local to reduce one's carbon footprint, and then talk about peak oil. They close the conversation with the Rick Ankiel story and the implications for the Barry Bonds saga.</itunes:subtitle>

<itunes:keywords>economics, Mike Munger,recycling,buy local,peak oil,baseball, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Mungergrabbag.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Mungergrabbag.mp3" length="31352998" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>1:05:19</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Epstein on Property Rights, Zoning and Kelo</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2007 07:45:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Richard Epstein, of the University of Chicago and Stanford's Hoover Institution, makes the case that many current zoning restrictions are essentially "takings" and property owners should receive compensation for the lost value of their land. He also discusses the Kelo case and the political economy of the regulation of land.</description>
<itunes:summary>Richard Epstein, of the University of Chicago and Stanford's Hoover Institution, makes the case that many current zoning restrictions are essentially "takings" and property owners should receive compensation for the lost value of their land. He also discusses the Kelo case and the political economy of the regulation of land.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Richard Epstein makes the case that many current zoning restrictions are essentially "takings" and property owners should receive compensation for the lost value of their land. He also discusses the Kelo case and the political economy of the regulation of land.</itunes:subtitle>

<itunes:keywords>economics, Richard Epstein,zoning,Kelo,property rights, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Epsteinzoning.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Epsteinzoning.mp3" length="19916799" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>41:29</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Cowen on Your Inner Economist</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2007 06:30:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Tyler Cowen, of George Mason University, talks about his new book, Discover Your Inner Economist: Use Incentives to Fall in Love, Survive Your Next Meeting, and Motivate Your Dentist. Cowen, legendary blogger at MarginalRevolution.com, talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about the economics of parenting, reading, dentistry, art museums and education. Highlights include Tyler's favorite art museum and what to see there along with the challenges of being a tourist in Morocco.</description>
<itunes:summary>Tyler Cowen, of George Mason University, talks about his new book, Discover Your Inner Economist: Use Incentives to Fall in Love, Survive Your Next Meeting, and Motivate Your Dentist. Cowen, legendary blogger at MarginalRevolution.com, talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about the economics of parenting, reading, dentistry, art museums and education. Highlights include Tyler's favorite art museum and what to see there along with the challenges of being a tourist in Morocco.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Tyler Cowen talks about his new book, Discover Your Inner Economist. Cowen, blogger at MarginalRevolution, talks with host Russ Roberts about the economics of parenting, reading, dentistry, art museums and education. Highlights include Tyler's favorite art museum along with the challenges of being a tourist in Morocco.</itunes:subtitle>

<itunes:keywords>economics, Tyler Cowen,inner economist,parenting,art,Morocco, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Coweneconomist.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Coweneconomist.mp3" length="28028968" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>58:23</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>George Shultz on Economics, Human Rights and the Fall of the Soviet Union</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2007 06:00:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>George Shultz, the Thomas W. and Susan B. Ford Distinguished Fellow at Stanford's Hoover Institution and Secretary of State under Ronald Reagan, talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about the role of economics in his career, the tension between morality and pragmatism in foreign policy, and the role of personalities and economics in diplomacy, particularly in US/Soviet relations in the 1980s.</description>
<itunes:summary>George Shultz, the Thomas W. and Susan B. Ford Distinguished Fellow at Stanford's Hoover Institution and Secretary of State under Ronald Reagan, talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about the role of economics in his career, the tension between morality and pragmatism in foreign policy, and the role of personalities and economics in diplomacy, particularly in US/Soviet relations in the 1980s.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>George Shultz, the Thomas W. and Susan B. Ford Distinguished Fellow at Stanford's Hoover Institution and Secretary of State under Ronald Reagan, talks with host Russ Roberts about the role of economics in his career, the tension between morality and pragmatism in foreign policy, and the role of personalities and economics in diplomacy, particularly in US/Soviet relations in the 1980s.</itunes:subtitle>

<itunes:keywords>economics, George Shultz,soviet union,secretary of state,ronald reagan, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Shultzeconomics.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Shultzeconomics.mp3" length="17190451" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>35:48</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Romer on Growth</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2007 06:30:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Paul Romer, Stanford University professor and Hoover Institution Senior Fellow talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about growth, China, innovation, and the role of human capital. Also discussed are ideas in creating growth, the idea that ideas allow for increasing returns, and intellectual property and how it should be treated. This 75 minute podcast is a wonderful introduction to thinking about what creates and sustains our standard of living in the modern world.</description>
<itunes:summary>Paul Romer, Stanford University professor and Hoover Institution Senior Fellow talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about growth, China, innovation, and the role of human capital. Also discussed are ideas in creating growth, the idea that ideas allow for increasing returns, and intellectual property and how it should be treated. This 75 minute podcast is a wonderful introduction to thinking about what creates and sustains our standard of living in the modern world.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Paul Romer talks with host Russ Roberts about growth, China, innovation, and the role of human capital. Also discussed are ideas in creating growth, the idea that ideas allow for increasing returns, and intellectual property and how it should be treated. This 75 minute podcast is a wonderful introduction to thinking about what creates and sustains our standard of living in the modern world.</itunes:subtitle>

<itunes:keywords>economics, Paul Romer,growth,human capital,property, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Romergrowth.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Romergrowth.mp3" length="37029719" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>1:17:08</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Gordon on Ants, Humans, the Division of Labor and Emergent Order</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2007 23:15:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Deborah M. Gordon, Professor of Biological Sciences at Stanford University, is an authority on ants and order that emerges without control or centralized authority. The conversation begins with what might be called the economics of ant colonies, how they manage to be organized without an organizer, the division of labor and the role of tradeoffs. The discussion then turns to the implications for human societies and the similarities and differences between human and natural orders.</description>
<itunes:summary>Deborah M. Gordon, Professor of Biological Sciences at Stanford University, is an authority on ants and order that emerges without control or centralized authority. The conversation begins with what might be called the economics of ant colonies, how they manage to be organized without an organizer, the division of labor and the role of tradeoffs. The discussion then turns to the implications for human societies and the similarities and differences between human and natural orders.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Deborah M. Gordon is an authority on ants and order that emerges without control or centralized authority. The conversation begins with what might be called the economics of ant colonies, how they manage to be organized without an organizer, the division of labor and the role of tradeoffs. The discussion then turns to the implications for human societies and the similarities and differences between human and natural orders.</itunes:subtitle>

<itunes:keywords>economics, Deborah M. Gordon,ant colonies,ants,order,organization, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Gordonants.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Gordonants.mp3" length="31757373" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>1:06:09</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Weingast on Violence, Power and a Theory of Nearly Everything</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2007 06:30:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Barry Weingast, Senior Fellow at Stanford University's Hoover Institution and the Ward C. Krebs Family Professor in the Department of Political Science at Stanford University, talks about the ideas in his forthcoming book with Doug North and John Wallis, A Conceptual Framework for Interpreting Recorded Human History. Weingast talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about how violence shapes political institutions, the role of competition in politics and economics, and why most development advice from successful nations fails to lift poor nations out of poverty.</description>
<itunes:summary>Barry Weingast, Senior Fellow at Stanford University's Hoover Institution and the Ward C. Krebs Family Professor in the Department of Political Science at Stanford University, talks about the ideas in his forthcoming book with Doug North and John Wallis, A Conceptual Framework for Interpreting Recorded Human History. Weingast talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about how violence shapes political institutions, the role of competition in politics and economics, and why most development advice from successful nations fails to lift poor nations out of poverty.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Barry Weingast talks about the ideas in his forthcoming book with Doug North and John Wallis, A Conceptual Framework for Interpreting Recorded Human History. Weingast and host Russ Roberts discuss how violence shapes political institutions, the role of competition in politics and economics, and why most development advice from successful nations fails to lift poor nations out of poverty.</itunes:subtitle>

<itunes:keywords>economics, Barry Weingast,power,politics,international development, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Weingastpower.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Weingastpower.mp3" length="31383300" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>1:05:22</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hanushek on Educational Quality and Economic Growth</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2007 06:00:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Eric Hanushek, Senior Fellow at the Hoover Institution, talks about his research on the impact of educational quality on economic growth. Past efforts to increase the economic growth rate of poor countries have focused on years of schooling, neglecting the quality and true education that needs to take place. Hanushek presents dramatic findings about the decisive nature of cognitive ability and knowledge in driving economic growth. Join us as Hanushek talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about his findings and the implications for public policy around the world and in the United States.</description>
<itunes:summary>Eric Hanushek, Senior Fellow at the Hoover Institution, talks about his research on the impact of educational quality on economic growth. Past efforts to increase the economic growth rate of poor countries have focused on years of schooling, neglecting the quality and true education that needs to take place. Hanushek presents dramatic findings about the decisive nature of cognitive ability and knowledge in driving economic growth. Join us as Hanushek talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about his findings and the implications for public policy around the world and in the United States.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Eric Hanushek talks about his research on the impact of educational quality on economic growth. Past efforts to increase the economic growth rate of poor countries have focused on years of schooling, neglecting the quality and true education involved. Hanushek presents dramatic findings about the decisive nature of cognitive ability and knowledge in driving economic growth.</itunes:subtitle>

<itunes:keywords>economics, Eric Hanushek,education,growth,quality,international, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Hanushekquality.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Hanushekquality.mp3" length="30315623" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>1:03:09</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Henderson on Disagreeable Economists</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2007 06:00:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>David Henderson, editor of the Concise Encyclopedia of Economics and a research fellow at Stanford's Hoover Institution, talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about when and why economists disagree. Harry Truman longed for a one-armed economist, one willing to go out on a limb and take an unequivocal position without adding "on the other hand...". Truman's view is often reflected in the public's view that economic knowledge is inherently ambiguous and that economists never agree on anything. Henderson claims that this view is wrong--that there is substantial agreement among economists on many scientific questions--while Roberts wonders whether this consensus is getting a bit frayed around the edges. The conversation highlights the challenges the everyday person faces in trying to know when and what to believe when economists take policy positions based on research. Is it biased or science?</description>
<itunes:summary>David Henderson, editor of the Concise Encyclopedia of Economics and a research fellow at Stanford's Hoover Institution, talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about when and why economists disagree. Harry Truman longed for a one-armed economist, one willing to go out on a limb and take an unequivocal position without adding "on the other hand...". Truman's view is often reflected in the public's view that economic knowledge is inherently ambiguous and that economists never agree on anything. Henderson claims that this view is wrong--that there is substantial agreement among economists on many scientific questions--while Roberts wonders whether this consensus is getting a bit frayed around the edges. The conversation highlights the challenges the everyday person faces in trying to know when and what to believe when economists take policy positions based on research. Is it biased or science?</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>David Henderson talks about when and why economists disagree. Is economics biased or science? The public's view is often that economic knowledge is inherently ambiguous and that economists never agree. Henderson claims that this view is wrong--that there is substantial agreement among economists on many scientific questions. Roberts wonders whether this consensus is fraying around the edges.</itunes:subtitle>

<itunes:keywords>economics, David Henderson,science,economists,disagreement, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Hendersoneconomists.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Hendersoneconomists.mp3" length="28887665" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>1:00:10</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Bueno de Mesquita on Reagan, Yeltsin, and the Strategy of Political Campaigning</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2007 06:00:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Bruce Bueno de Mesquita, NYU and the Hoover Institute, talks about the political economy of political campaigns and his forthcoming book, The Strategy of Campaigning: Lessons from Ronald Reagan and Boris Yeltsin. He talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about the different strategies politicians pursue in attracting support from voters and party delegates, the persistence of negative campaigning, the cost to politicians of sticking to their principles and how the political choices of Reagan and Yeltsin intersected to end the Cold War and dissolve the Soviet Union.</description>
<itunes:summary>Bruce Bueno de Mesquita, NYU and the Hoover Institute, talks about the political economy of political campaigns and his forthcoming book, The Strategy of Campaigning: Lessons from Ronald Reagan and Boris Yeltsin. He talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about the different strategies politicians pursue in attracting support from voters and party delegates, the persistence of negative campaigning, the cost to politicians of sticking to their principles and how the political choices of Reagan and Yeltsin intersected to end the Cold War and dissolve the Soviet Union.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Bruce Bueno de Mesquita talks about the political economy of political campaigns and his forthcoming book, The Strategy of Campaigning. He talks with host Russ Roberts about the different strategies politicians pursue, the persistence of negative campaigning, the cost to politicians of sticking to their principles and how the political choices of Reagan and Yeltsin intersected to end the Cold War and dissolve the Soviet Union.</itunes:subtitle>

<itunes:keywords>economics, Bruce Bueno de Mesquita,politics,campaigning,reagan,yeltsin, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/BuenodeMesquitacampaign.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/BuenodeMesquitacampaign.mp3" length="32186826" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>1:07:03</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Ticket Prices and Scalping</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2007 06:45:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>EconTalk host Russ Roberts talks about scalping and visits AT&amp;T Park hours before Major League Baseball's All-Star Game to talk with a scalper, a merchandiser, a fan, and the police about prices, tickets, baseball and the law.</description>
<itunes:summary>EconTalk host Russ Roberts talks about scalping and visits AT&amp;T Park hours before Major League Baseball's All-Star Game to talk with a scalper, a merchandiser, a fan, and the police about prices, tickets, baseball and the law.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>EconTalk host Russ Roberts talks about scalping and visits AT&amp;T Park hours before Major League Baseball's All-Star Game to talk with a scalper, a merchandiser, a fan, and the police about prices, tickets, baseball and the law.</itunes:subtitle>

<itunes:keywords>economics, Russ Roberts, scalping, sports, baseball, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Robertsscalping.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Robertsscalping.mp3" length="19433011" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>40:29</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Leamer on Outsourcing and Globalization</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2007 06:30:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Is outsourcing good for America? How does foreign competition affect wages in the United States? Ed Leamer, professor of economics at UCLA, talks about the effects of outsourcing on wages, jobs, and the U.S. standard of living. Drawing on a review of Thomas Friedman's The World is Flat, Leamer talks with host Russ Roberts about technology, trade, productivity and inequality.</description>
<itunes:summary>Is outsourcing good for America? How does foreign competition affect wages in the United States? Ed Leamer, professor of economics at UCLA, talks about the effects of outsourcing on wages, jobs, and the U.S. standard of living. Drawing on a review of Thomas Friedman's The World is Flat, Leamer talks with host Russ Roberts about technology, trade, productivity and inequality.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Is outsourcing good for America? How does foreign competition affect wages in the United States? Ed Leamer, professor of economics at UCLA, talks about the effects of outsourcing on wages, jobs, and the U.S. standard of living. Drawing on a review of Thomas Friedman's The World is Flat, Leamer talks with host Russ Roberts about technology, trade, productivity and inequality.</itunes:subtitle>

<itunes:keywords>economics,Ed Leamer,outsourcing,flat world,offshoring,India,China,econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Leameroutsourcing.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Leameroutsourcing.mp3" length="31275048" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>1:05:09</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Munger on Recycling</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>


<pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2007 05:30:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Mike Munger, professor of economics and political science at Duke University and frequent guest of EconTalk, talks with host Russ Roberts about the economics and politics of recycling. Munger argues that recycling can save resources, of course, but it can also require more resources than production from scratch. Some curbside recycling, for example, makes sense, while other forms (such as green glass) may be akin to a form of religious expression rather than a wise policy that is environmentally productive. The conversation is based on Munger's recent essay at the Library of Economics and Liberty.</description>
<itunes:summary>Mike Munger, professor of economics and political science at Duke University and frequent guest of EconTalk, talks with host Russ Roberts about the economics and politics of recycling. Munger argues that recycling can save resources, of course, but it can also require more resources than production from scratch. Some curbside recycling, for example, makes sense, while other forms (such as green glass) may be akin to a form of religious expression rather than a wise policy that is environmentally productive. The conversation is based on Munger's recent essay at the Library of Economics and Liberty.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Mike Munger talks about the economics and politics of recycling. Munger argues that recycling can save resources, but it can also require more resources than production from scratch. Some curbside recycling, for example, makes sense, while other forms (such as green glass) may be akin to a form of religious expression rather than a wise policy that is environmentally productive. The conversation is based on Munger's recent essay at the Library of Economics and Liberty.</itunes:subtitle>

<itunes:keywords>economics, Mike Munger, environment, glass, regulation, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Mungerrecycling.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Mungerrecycling.mp3" length="30004452" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>1:02:30</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Caplan on the Myth of the Rational Voter</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2007 06:45:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Bryan Caplan, of George Mason University and blogger at EconLog, talks about his book, The Myth of the Rational Voter: Why Democracies Choose Bad Policies. Caplan argues that democracies work well in giving voters what they want but unfortunately, what voters want isn't particularly wise, especially when it comes to economic policy. He outlines a series of systematic biases we often have on economic topics and explains why we have little or no incentive to improve our understanding of the world and vote wisely. So, it's not special interests that are messing things up but the very incentives that lie at the heart of a vote-based system. This is a disturbing and provocative lens for viewing political outcomes.</description>
<itunes:summary>Bryan Caplan, of George Mason University and blogger at EconLog, talks about his book, The Myth of the Rational Voter: Why Democracies Choose Bad Policies. Caplan argues that democracies work well in giving voters what they want but unfortunately, what voters want isn't particularly wise, especially when it comes to economic policy. He outlines a series of systematic biases we often have on economic topics and explains why we have little or no incentive to improve our understanding of the world and vote wisely. So, it's not special interests that are messing things up but the very incentives that lie at the heart of a vote-based system. This is a disturbing and provocative lens for viewing political outcomes.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Bryan Caplan talks about his book, The Myth of the Rational Voter. Caplan argues that democracies work well in giving voters what they want, but what voters want isn't particularly wise, especially when it comes to economic policy. He outlines a series of systematic biases we often have on economic topics and explains why we have little or no incentive to improve our understanding of the world and vote wisely.</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:keywords>economics, Bryan Caplan, democracy, voting, bias, psychology, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Caplanmyth.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Caplanmyth.mp3" length="38952541" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>1:21:09</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Weinberger on Everything is Miscellaneous and the Wonderful World of Digital Information</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2007 06:30:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Author David Weinberger, a fellow at Harvard's Berkman Institute for Internet and Society, talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about the ideas in his latest book, Everything is Miscellaneous: The Power of the New Digital Disorder. Topics include the differences between how we organize and think about physical and digital information, the power of the internet to let us consume information in unique and customized ways and the implications for retailing, politics and education.</description>
<itunes:summary>Author David Weinberger, a fellow at Harvard's Berkman Institute for Internet and Society, talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about the ideas in his latest book, Everything is Miscellaneous: The Power of the New Digital Disorder. Topics include the differences between how we organize and think about physical and digital information, the power of the internet to let us consume information in unique and customized ways and the implications for retailing, politics and education.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Author David Weinberger talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about the ideas in his latest book, Everything is Miscellaneous. Topics include the differences between how we organize and think about physical and digital information, the power of the internet to let us consume information in unique and customized ways and the implications for retailing, politics and education.</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:keywords>economics, David Weinberger, digital information, Staples, merchandising, internet, Wikipedia, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Weinbergerinformation.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Weinbergerinformation.mp3" length="35939891" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>1:14:52</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Dan Pink on How Half Your Brain Can Save Your Job</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2007 06:30:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Author Dan Pink, talks about the ideas in his book, A Whole New Mind: Why Right-Brainers Will Rule the Future. He argues that the skills of the right side of the brain--skills such as creativity, empathy, contextual thinking and big picture thinking--are going to become increasingly important as a response to competition from low-wage workers overseas and our growing standard of living.</description>
<itunes:summary>Author Dan Pink, talks about the ideas in his book, A Whole New Mind: Why Right-Brainers Will Rule the Future. He argues that the skills of the right side of the brain--skills such as creativity, empathy, contextual thinking and big picture thinking--are going to become increasingly important as a response to competition from low-wage workers overseas and our growing standard of living.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Author Dan Pink talks about the ideas in his book, A Whole New Mind. He argues that the skills of the right side of the brain--skills such as creativity, empathy, contextual thinking and big picture thinking--are going to become increasingly important as a response to competition from low-wage workers overseas and our growing standard of living.</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:keywords>economics, Dan Pink, right brained, mind, story, symphony, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Pinkmind.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Pinkmind.mp3" length="32266656" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>1:07:13</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Shlaes on the Great Depression</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2007 06:30:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Amity Shlaes, Bloomberg columnist and visiting senior fellow at the Council on Foreign Relations, talks about her new book, The Forgotten Man: A New History of the Great Depression. She and EconTalk host Russ Roberts discuss Herbert Hoover, Franklin Delano Roosevelt, the economics of the New Deal and the class warfare of the 1930s.</description>
<itunes:summary>Amity Shlaes, Bloomberg columnist and visiting senior fellow at the Council on Foreign Relations, talks about her new book, The Forgotten Man: A New History of the Great Depression. She and EconTalk host Russ Roberts discuss Herbert Hoover, Franklin Delano Roosevelt, the economics of the New Deal and the class warfare of the 1930s.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Amity Shlaes talks about her new book, The Forgotten Man: A New History of the Great Depression. She and host Russ Roberts discuss Herbert Hoover, Franklin Delano Roosevelt, the economics of the New Deal and the class warfare of the 1930s.</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:keywords>economics, Amity Shlaes, forgotten man, great depression, roosevelt, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Shlaesgreatdepression.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Shlaesgreatdepression.mp3" length="31922467" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>1:05:30</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hanson on Health</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2007 05:45:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Robin Hanson, of George Mason University, argues that health care is different, but not in the usual ways people claim. He describes a set of paradoxical empirical findings in the study of health care and tries to explain these paradoxes in a unified way. One of his arguments is that the human brain evolved in ways that make it hard for us to be rational about health care. He also discusses using prediction markets as a way of designing health care policy.</description>
<itunes:summary>Robin Hanson, of George Mason University, argues that health care is different, but not in the usual ways people claim. He describes a set of paradoxical empirical findings in the study of health care and tries to explain these paradoxes in a unified way. One of his arguments is that the human brain evolved in ways that make it hard for us to be rational about health care. He also discusses using prediction markets as a way of designing health care policy.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Robin Hanson argues that health care is different, but not in the usual ways people claim. He describes paradoxical empirical findings and tries to explain these paradoxes in a unified way. He argues that the human brain evolved in ways that make it hard for us to be rational about health care.</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:keywords>economics, Robin Hanson, health care, prediction markets, evolution, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Hansonhealth.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Hansonhealth.mp3" length="34689148" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>1:12:16</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Vernon Smith on Markets and Experimental Economics</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2007 06:00:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Vernon Smith, Professor of Economics at George Mason University and the 2002 Nobel Laureate in Economics, talks about experimental economics, markets, risk, behavioral economics and the evolution of his career.</description>
<itunes:summary>Vernon Smith, Professor of Economics at George Mason University and the 2002 Nobel Laureate in Economics, talks about experimental economics, markets, risk, behavioral economics and the evolution of his career.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Vernon Smith, Professor of Economics at George Mason University and the 2002 Nobel Laureate in Economics, talks about experimental economics, markets, risk, behavioral economics and the evolution of his career.</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:keywords>economics, Vernon Smith, supply and demand, Nobel, experiment, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Smithexperimental.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Smithexperimental.mp3" length="15895719" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>1:06:13</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Sunstein on Infotopia, Information and Decision-Making</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2007 05:45:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Cass Sunstein of the University of Chicago talks about the ideas in his latest book, Infotopia: How Many Minds Produce Knowledge. What are the best ways to get the information needed to make wise decisions when that information is spread out among an organization's members or a society's citizens? He argues that prediction markets can help both politicians and business leaders make better decisions and discusses the surprising ways they're already being used today. Deliberation, the standard way we often gather information at various kinds of meetings, has some unpleasant biases that hamper its usefulness relative to surveys and incentive-based alternatives.</description>
<itunes:summary>Cass Sunstein of the University of Chicago talks about the ideas in his latest book, Infotopia. What are the best ways to get the information needed to make wise decisions when that information is spread out among an organization's members or a society's citizens? He argues that prediction markets can help both politicians and business leaders make better decisions and discusses the surprising ways they're already being used today. Deliberation, the standard way we often gather information at various kinds of meetings, has some unpleasant biases that hamper its usefulness relative to surveys and incentive-based alternatives.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Cass Sunstein talks about the ideas in his latest book, Infotopia. What are the best ways to get the information needed to make wise decisions when that information is spread out? He argues that prediction markets can help both politicians and business leaders make better decisions. Deliberation, the standard way we often gather information at various kinds of meetings, has some biases.</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:keywords>economics, Cass Sunstein, prediction markets, book review, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Sunsteininformation.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Sunsteininformation.mp3" length="15617463" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>1:05:04</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Allison on Strategy, Profits, and Self-Interest</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2007 07:30:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>John Allison, CEO of BB and T Bank, lays out his business philosophy arguing for the virtues of profits, self-interest and production. His definition of justice, one of the core values of his firm, is that those who produce more, get more. He argues that Bill Gates would do more for the world improving Microsoft than running his foundation and giving away money. Allison praises Atlas Shrugged and refuses to let his bank make loans to companies that use eminent domain to acquire property. Is this any way to run a company? Does Allison really run his company this way? How does he deal with the gap between his philosophy and our popular culture's view of business and profits? Listen as Allison and host Russ Roberts discuss BB and T's unusual business strategy.</description>
<itunes:summary>John Allison, CEO of BB and T Bank, lays out his business philosophy arguing for the virtues of profits, self-interest and production. His definition of justice, one of the core values of his firm, is that those who produce more, get more. He argues that Bill Gates would do more for the world improving Microsoft than running his foundation and giving away money. Allison praises Atlas Shrugged and refuses to let his bank make loans to companies that use eminent domain to acquire property. Is this any way to run a company? Does Allison really run his company this way? How does he deal with the gap between his philosophy and our popular culture's view of business and profits? Listen as Allison and host Russ Roberts discuss BB and T's unusual business strategy.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>John Allison, CEO of BB and T Bank, lays out his business philosophy arguing for the virtues of profits, self-interest and production. His definition of justice, one of the core values of his firm, is that those who produce more, get more. He argues that Bill Gates would do more for the world improving Microsoft than running his foundation and giving away money. Allison praises Atlas Shrugged and refuses to let his bank make loans to companies that use eminent domain to acquire property. Is this any way to run a company?</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:keywords>economics, John Allison, banking, Ayn Rand, eminent domain, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Allisonstrategy.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Allisonstrategy.mp3" length="13724839" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>57:11</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Taleb on Black Swans</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2007 07:30:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Nassim Taleb talks about the challenges of coping with uncertainty, predicting events, and understanding history. This wide-ranging conversation looks at investment, health, history and other areas where data play a key role. Taleb, the author of Fooled By Randomness and The Black Swan, imagines two countries, Mediocristan and Extremistan where the ability to understand the past and predict the future is radically different. Taleb's contention is that we often bring our intuition from Mediocristan for the events of Extremistan, leading us to error. The result is a tendency to be blind-sided by the unexpected.</description>
<itunes:summary>Nassim Taleb talks about the challenges of coping with uncertainty, predicting events, and understanding history. This wide-ranging conversation looks at investment, health, history and other areas where data play a key role. Taleb, the author of Fooled By Randomness and The Black Swan, imagines two countries, Mediocristan and Extremistan where the ability to understand the past and predict the future is radically different. Taleb's contention is that we often bring our intuition from Mediocristan for the events of Extremistan, leading us to error. The result is a tendency to be blind-sided by the unexpected.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Nassim Taleb talks about the challenges of coping with uncertainty, predicting events, and understanding history. This wide-ranging conversation looks at investment, health, history and other areas where data play a key role.</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:keywords>economics, Nassim Taleb, black swan, fooled by randomness, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Talebswan.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Talebswan.mp3" length="20041352" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>1:23:30</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Rabushka on the Flat Tax</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2007 08:45:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Alvin Rabushka of Stanford University's Hoover Institution lays out the case for the flat tax, a reform of the current system that would replace the 66,000 page U.S. tax code with a single rate and no deductions other than personal exemptions. An individual tax return would fit on a simple postcard. Rabushka discusses the economic changes that would come with such a reform and the adoption of the flat tax around the world since Rabushka and Robert Hall proposed the idea in 1981.</description>
<itunes:summary>Alvin Rabushka of Stanford University's Hoover Institution lays out the case for the flat tax, a reform of the current system that would replace the 66,000 page U.S. tax code with a single rate and no deductions other than personal exemptions. An individual tax return would fit on a simple postcard. Rabushka discusses the economic changes that would come with such a reform and the adoption of the flat tax around the world since Rabushka and Robert Hall proposed the idea in 1981.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Alvin Rabushka lays out the case for the flat tax, a reform of the current system that would replace the 66,000 page U.S. tax code with a single rate and no deductions other than personal exemptions. Rabushka discusses the economic changes that would come with such a reform and the adoption of the flat tax around the world since he and Robert Hall proposed the idea in 1981.</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:keywords>economics, Alvin Rabushka, taxation, flat tax, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Rabushkataxes.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Rabushkataxes.mp3" length="15427187" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>1:04:16</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Boudreaux on the Economics of "Buy Local"</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2007 05:45:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Proponents of buying local argue that it is better to buy from the local hardware store owner and nearby farmer than from the Big Box chain store or the grocery store headquartered out of town because the money from the purchase is more likely to "stay in the local economy." Don Boudreaux of George Mason University talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about the economics of this idea. Is it better to buy local than from a seller based out of town? Is it better to buy American than to buy foreign products? Does the money matter? In this conversation, Boudreaux and Roberts pierce through the veil of money to expose what trade, whether local, national, or international, really accomplishes.</description>
<itunes:summary>Proponents of buying local argue that it is better to buy from the local hardware store owner and nearby farmer than from the Big Box chain store or the grocery store headquartered out of town because the money from the purchase is more likely to "stay in the local economy." Don Boudreaux of George Mason University talks with EconTalk host Russ Roberts about the economics of this idea. Is it better to buy local than from a seller based out of town? Is it better to buy American than to buy foreign products? Does the money matter? In this conversation, Boudreaux and Roberts pierce through the veil of money to expose what trade, whether local, national, or international, really accomplishes.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Don Boudreaux of George Mason U. talks with host Russ Roberts about the economics of buying local. Is it better to buy local than from a seller based out of town? Is it better to buy American than to buy foreign products? Does where the money goes matter?</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:keywords>economics, Don Boudreaux, trade deficit, immigrants, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Boudreauxlocal.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Boudreauxlocal.mp3" length="13407608" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>55:51</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Bogle on Investing</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2007 07:15:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>The legendary John Bogle, founder of the Vanguard Group and creator of the index mutual fund, talks about the Great Depression, the riskiness of bond funds, how he created the Index 500 mutual fund--now the largest single mutual fund in the world--how the study of economics changed his life and ours, and Sarbanes-Oxley. At the end of the conversation, he reflects on his life and career.</description>
<itunes:summary>The legendary John Bogle, founder of the Vanguard Group and creator of the index mutual fund, talks about the Great Depression, the riskiness of bond funds, how he created the Index 500 mutual fund--now the largest single mutual fund in the world--how the study of economics changed his life and ours, and Sarbanes-Oxley. At the end of the conversation, he reflects on his life and career.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>John Bogle, founder of the Vanguard Group and creator of the index mutual fund, talks about the Great Depression, bond funds risk, how he created the Index 500 mutual fund, how the study of economics changed his life, and Sarbanes-Oxley</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:keywords>economics, John Bogle, mutual funds, Sarbanes-Oxley, Great Depression, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Bogleinvesting.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Bogleinvesting.mp3" length="14042279" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>58:30</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Mike Munger on the Division of Labor</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2007 06:30:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Mike Munger of Duke University and EconTalk host Russ Roberts talk about specialization, the role of technology in aiding specialization and how the division of labor creates wealth.</description>
<itunes:summary>Mike Munger of Duke University and EconTalk host Russ Roberts talk about specialization, the role of technology in aiding specialization and how the division of labor creates wealth.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Mike Munger of Duke University and EconTalk host Russ Roberts talk about specialization, the role of technology in aiding specialization and how the division of labor creates wealth.</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:keywords>economics, Mike Munger, Adam Smith, specialization, division of labor, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Mungerlabor.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Mungerlabor.mp3" length="14788963" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>1:01:37</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Kevin Kelly on the Future of the Web and Everything Else</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2007 06:30:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Author Kevin Kelly talks about the role of technology in our lives, the future of the web, how to time travel, the wisdom of the hive, the economics of reputation, the convergence of the biological and the mechanical, and his impact on the movies The Matrix and Minority Report.</description>
<itunes:summary>Author Kevin Kelly talks about the role of technology in our lives, the future of the web, how to time travel, the wisdom of the hive, the economics of reputation, the convergence of the biological and the mechanical, and his impact on the movies The Matrix and Minority Report.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Author Kevin Kelly talks about technology and the web, time travel, the wisdom of the hive, the convergence of biology and mechanics, and his impact on The Matrix and Minority Report.</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:keywords>economics, Kevin Kelly, DNA computing, hive, The Matrix, Minority Report, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Kellyweb.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Kellyweb.mp3" length="16774060" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>1:09:53</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>David Leonhardt on the Media</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2007 07:00:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>David Leonhardt of the New York Times talks with Russ Roberts about media bias, competition between old and new media, global warming, and the role of information as an incentive to provide better health care.</description>
<itunes:summary>David Leonhardt, of the New York Times talks with Russ Roberts about media bias, competition between old and new media, global warming, and the role of information as an incentive to provide better health care.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>David Leonhardt, of the New York Times talks with Russ Roberts about media bias, competition between old and new media, global warming, and the role of information as an incentive to provide better health care.</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:keywords>economics, David Leonhardt, media bias, blogosphere, global warming, heart attacks, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Leonhardtmedia.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Leonhardtmedia.mp3" length="13853153" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>57:43</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Cowen on Liberty, Art, Food and Everything Else in Between</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2007 07:15:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Tyler Cowen, co-blogger (with Alex Tabarrok) at MarginalRevolution.com, talks about liberty, global warming, using the courts vs. regulation to protect people, the challenges of leading a country out of poverty, the political economy of cuisine, and a quick overview of the Washington, DC. art museum scene.</description>
<itunes:summary>Tyler Cowen, co-blogger (with Alex Tabarrok) at MarginalRevolution.com, talks about liberty, global warming, using the courts vs. regulation to protect people, the challenges of leading a country out of poverty, the political economy of cuisine, and a quick overview of the Washington, DC. art museum scene.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Tyler Cowen, MarginalRevolution.com blogger, talks about liberty, global warming, courts vs. regulation, developing countries, cuisine, and art.</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:keywords>economics, Tyler Cowen, art, food, public choice, property rights, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Cowenart.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Cowenart.mp3" length="13325793" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>55:31</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Easterbrook on the American Standard of Living</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2007 06:15:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Author Gregg Easterbrook talks about the ideas in his latest book, The Progress Paradox: How Life Gets Better While People Feel Worse. How has life changed in America over the last century? Is the average person getting ahead or are the rich taking all the gains? Easterbrook argues that life is better for the average American in almost every dimension. The paradox is that despite those gains, we don't seem much happier.</description>
<itunes:summary>Author Gregg Easterbrook talks about the ideas in his latest book, The Progress Paradox: How Life Gets Better While People Feel Worse. How has life changed in America over the last century? Is the average person getting ahead or are the rich taking all the gains? Easterbrook argues that life is better for the average American in almost every dimension. The paradox is that despite those gains, we don't seem much happier.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Author Gregg Easterbrook talks about the ideas in his latest book, The Progress Paradox. Is the average person getting ahead or are the rich taking all the gains? Easterbrook argues that life is better for the average American in almost every dimension. Yet, despite those gains, we don't seem much happier.</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:keywords>economics, Gregg Easterbrook, standard of living, happiness, econlib</itunes:keywords>


<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/EasterbrookAmerica.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/EasterbrookAmerica.mp3" length="13289430" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>55:22</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Viviana Zelizer on Money and Intimacy</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2007 07:00:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Viviana Zelizer, Princeton University sociologist, talks about the ideas in her new book, The Purchase of Intimacy. Does money ruin intimacy? Does intimacy ruin our commercial transactions? Zelizer and host Russ Roberts have a lively conversation on the sometimes contentious border between economics and sociology.</description>
<itunes:summary>Viviana Zelizer, Princeton University sociologist, talks about the ideas in her new book, The Purchase of Intimacy. Does money ruin intimacy? Does intimacy ruin our commercial transactions? Zelizer and host Russ Roberts have a lively conversation on the sometimes contentious border between economics and sociology.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Viviana Zelizer talks about the ideas in her new book, The Purchase of Intimacy. Does money ruin intimacy? Does intimacy ruin our commercial transactions? Zelizer and host Russ Roberts converse on the sometimes contentious border between economics and sociology.</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:keywords>economics, Viviana Zelizer, intimacy, money, sociology, econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Zelizermoney.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Zelizermoney.mp3" length="13195703" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>54:58</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Richard Epstein on Property Rights and Drug Patents</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2007 06:30:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Richard Epstein of the University of Chicago and Stanford University's Hoover Institution talks about property rights, drug patents, the FDA, and the ideas in his latest book, Overdose: How Excessive Government Regulation Stifles Pharmaceutical Innovation from Yale University Press.</description>
<itunes:summary>Richard Epstein of the University of Chicago and Stanford University's Hoover Institution talks about property rights, drug patents, the FDA, and the ideas in his latest book, Overdose: How Excessive Government Regulation Stifles Pharmaceutical Innovation from Yale University Press.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Richard Epstein talks about property rights, drug patents, the FDA, and the ideas in his latest book, Overdose: How Excessive Government Regulation Stifles Pharmaceutical Innovation, Yale U. Press.</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:keywords>economics Richard Epstein, drugs, patents, FDA, government policy econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Epsteindrugs.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Epsteindrugs.mp3" length="15888718" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>1:06:12</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Bruce Bueno de Mesquita on Democracies and Dictatorships</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2007 06:15:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Bruce Bueno de Mesquita of NYU and Stanford University's Hoover Institution talks about the incentives facing dictators and democratic leaders. Both have to face competition from rivals. Both try to please their constituents and cronies to stay in power. He applies his insights to foreign aid, the Middle East, Venezuela, the potential for China's evolution to a more democratic system, and Cuba. Along the way, he explains why true democracy is more than just elections--it depends crucially on freedom of assembly and freedom of the press.</description>
<itunes:summary>Bruce Bueno de Mesquita of NYU and Stanford University's Hoover Institution talks about the incentives facing dictators and democratic leaders. Both have to face competition from rivals. Both try to please their constituents and cronies to stay in power. He applies his insights to foreign aid, the Middle East, Venezuela, the potential for China's evolution to a more democratic system, and Cuba. Along the way, he explains why true democracy is more than just elections--it depends crucially on freedom of assembly and freedom of the press.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Bruce Bueno de Mesquita  talks about the incentives facing dictators and democratic leaders. Both have to face competition from rivals. Both try to please their constituents and cronies to stay in power. He applies his insights to foreign aid, the Middle East, Venezuela, the potential for China's evolution to a more democratic system, and Cuba. </itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:keywords>economics Bruce Bueno de Mesquita, democracy, autocracy, dictatorship econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/BuenodeMesquitademocracy.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/BuenodeMesquitademocracy.mp3" length="16060604" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>1:06:55</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Lucas on Growth and Poverty</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2007 07:15:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Bob Lucas, Nobel Laureate and professor of economics at the University of Chicago talks about wealth and poverty, what affects living standards around the world and over time, the causes of business cycles and the role of the money in our economy. Along the way, he talks about Jane Jacobs, immigration, and Milton Friedman's influence on his career.</description>
<itunes:summary>Bob Lucas, Nobel Laureate and professor of economics at the University of Chicago talks about wealth and poverty, what affects living standards around the world and over time, the causes of business cycles and the role of the money in our economy. Along the way, he talks about Jane Jacobs, immigration, and Milton Friedman's influence on his career.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Bob Lucas, Nobel Laureate and professor of economics at the U. of Chicago, talks about wealth, poverty, and the subtle and not-so-subtle keys to growth. He also talks about the work of Jane Jacobs, immigration, and Milton Friedman.</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:keywords>economics Bob Lucas, growth, poverty, Nobel Prize econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Lucasgrowth.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Lucasgrowth.mp3" length="11578201" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>48:14</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Michael Lewis on the Hidden Economics of Baseball and Football </title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2007 06:30:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Michael Lewis talks about the economics of sports--the financial and decision-making side of baseball and football--using the insights from his bestselling books on baseball and football: Moneyball and The Blind Side. Along the way he discusses the implications of Moneyball for the movie business and other industries, the peculiar ways that Moneyball influenced the strategies of baseball teams, the corruption of college football, and the challenge and tragedy of kids who live on the streets with little education or prospects for success.</description>
<itunes:summary>Michael Lewis talks about the economics of sports--the financial and decision-making side of baseball and football--using the insights from his bestselling books on baseball and football: Moneyball and The Blind Side. Along the way he discusses the implications of Moneyball for the movie business and other industries, the peculiar ways that Moneyball influenced the strategies of baseball teams, the corruption of college football, and the challenge and tragedy of kids who live on the streets with little education or prospects for success.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Michael Lewis talks about the economics of sports--the financial and decision-making side of baseball and football--using the insights from his bestselling books on baseball and football: Moneyball and The Blind Side.</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:keywords>economics Michael Lewis, football, baseball econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Lewissports.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Lewissports.mp3" length="18227931" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>1:15:56</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Greg Mankiw on Gasoline Taxes, Keynes and Macroeconomics</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2007 06:15:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Greg Mankiw of Harvard University and Greg Mankiw's Blog talks about the state of modern macroeconomics and Keynes vs. the Chicago School. He defends his proposal to raise gasoline taxes and discusses the politics of tax policy.</description>

<itunes:summary>Greg Mankiw of Harvard University and Greg Mankiw's Blog talks about the state of modern macroeconomics and Keynes vs. the Chicago School. He defends his proposal to raise gasoline taxes and discusses the politics of tax policy.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Greg Mankiw talks about the state of modern macroeconomics and Keynes vs. the Chicago School. He defends his proposal to raise gasoline taxes and discusses the politics of tax policy.</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:keywords>economics Greg Mankiw, Pigou Club, taxes, Keynesian economics econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Mankiwmacro.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Mankiwmacro.mp3" length="14499213" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>1:00:24</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Bruce Yandle on Bootleggers and Baptists</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2007 08:10:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Bruce Yandle of Clemson University explains why politics makes such strange bedfellows and the often peculiar alliance of self-interested special interests with more altruistic motives. He uses his insights to explain some of the seemingly perverse but politically understandable effects of the Clean Air Act, the tobacco settlement and other regulation.</description>
<itunes:summary>Bruce Yandle of Clemson University explains why politics makes such strange bedfellows and the often peculiar alliance of self-interested special interests with more altruistic motives. He uses his insights to explain some of the seemingly perverse but politically understandable effects of the Clean Air Act, the tobacco settlement and other regulation.</itunes:summary>
<itunes:subtitle>Bruce Yandle explains why politics makes such strange bedfellows and the often peculiar alliance of self-interested special interests with more altruistic motives. He uses his insights to explain some of the seemingly perverse but politically understandable effects of the Clean Air Act, the tobacco settlement and other regulation.</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:keywords>economics Bruce Yandle, Clean Air Act, political science econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/y2007/Yandleregulation.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/y2007/Yandleregulation.mp3" length="16511582" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>1:08:47</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>

<item>
<title>Munger on Price Gouging</title>

<itunes:author>EconTalk: Russ Roberts</itunes:author>

<pubDate>Mon, 8 Jan 2007 12:15:00 EST</pubDate>

<description>Mike Munger of Duke University recounts the harrowing (and fascinating) experience of being in the path of a hurricane and the economic forces that were set in motion as a result. One of the most important is the import of urgent supplies when thousands of people are without electricity. Should prices be allowed to rise freely or should the government restrict prices? Listen in as Munger and EconTalk host Russ Roberts discuss the human side of economics after a catastrophe.</description>
<itunes:summary>Mike Munger of Duke University recounts the harrowing (and fascinating) experience of being in the path of a hurricane and the economic forces that were set in motion as a result. One of the most important is the import of urgent supplies when thousands of people are without electricity. Should prices be allowed to rise freely or should the government restrict prices? Listen in as Munger and EconTalk host Russ Roberts discuss the human side of economics after a catastrophe.</itunes:summary>

<itunes:subtitle>Mike Munger recounts the harrowing (and fascinating) experience of being in the path of a hurricane and the economic forces that were set in motion as a result. One of the most important is the import of urgent supplies when thousands of people are without electricity. Should prices be allowed to rise freely or should the government restrict prices?</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:keywords>economics Mike Munger, hurricanes, price gouging econlib</itunes:keywords>

<guid>http://www.econlib.org/library/Downloads/Mungergouging.mp3</guid>
<enclosure url="http://files.libertyfund.org/econtalk/Mungergouging.mp3" length="14433176" type="audio/mpeg" />
<itunes:duration>1:00:08</itunes:duration> 
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
</item>



</channel>
</rss>

